

# Kumar R

Sr. Application Developer

Around 5+ years of experience in web and database application. Experience in AJAX, REST web-services, JSON. Involved in the Software Life Cycle phases like AGILE and technical practices like Continuous Integration and Continuous Delivery. ReactJS Trainer for freshers at Contus Support Interactive Pvt. Ltd

🔀 kumar.rt1990@gmail.com

+91 9865469175

Chennai, India

argutech.blogspot.in

n linkedin.com/in/kumar-ramalingam

# **SKILLS**

ReactJS Redux ReactNative ES6 PolymerJS ExpressJS NodeJS AngularJS 1.X MongoDB MySQL

HTML5 CSS3 Bootstrap Material UI Laravel Framework Lumen Joomla WordPress Git Bitbucket

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# **Sr. Application Developer**

Contus Support Interactive Pvt. Ltd

03/2016 - Present

Star Performer Award

- Project handling on all phases of development life cycle, from analysis to deployment on production environment, to post-release support
- Extensive work experience in Jest, AWS cloud services. Developing generic solutions and reusable code libraries.

# Application Developer

infySEC Solutions Pvt. Ltd

07/2015 - 02/2016

**Outstanding Performer Award** 

Requirement gathering, Database design, Development and end to end testing

# Application Developer W3Cert Technologies

06/2013 - 06/2015

Good appreciation from clients

Requirement gathering, Database design, Development and end to end testing

## **PROJECTS DETAILS**

# Versa Network (Python & ReactJS)

- The project is about development of Saas Ecommerce Portal for Versa Networks, an innovative vendor in the SD-WAN and SD-Security market.
- They intended to sell their two main products via the e-commerce portal, to their enterprise customers, where Versa Infrastructure will provision and support the Virtual Private Network over the Internet as a managed service.
- Involved in developing UI using HTML5
- Played key role in development of a well responsive single page application using ReactJS.
- Used Redux to create store to synchronize data with server.
- Took responsibility for particular module and completed it successfully.

### **PROJECTS DETAILS**

#### Job Portal (NodeJS & ReactJS)

- Job portal for employer to post their Job and employee can view and apply for the Job.
- Involved in developing UI using HTML5 and Bootstrap.
- Involved in the development of presentation layer of both frontend ReactJS and backend NodeJS for the Application.

#### GetSpeed (Laravel & Lumen & ReactJS)

- The project objective is to streaming live streaming videos and upload to recorded videos and ads Management and CMS Management and selling the products, orders and stock history.
- Prepared DB Schema & involved in service architectural design.
- Involved in the development of presentation layer of both frontend and backend for the Application with ReactJS
- Micro Services : Admin, Frontend, Ads, Livestream, CMS Micro Services

#### MoverBee (Laravel & AngularJS)

- The project objective is to Customer can book a delivery through this app where delivery individual either from the registered firm or an Individual would be able to pick it up and deliver
- Prepared DB Schema & involved in service architectural design
- Implemented the Laravel Test Cases.
- Micro Services : Admin, Frontend, Customers, Drivers, Orders, Pricing, Notifications, Review Micro Services.

#### TimeSheet Management (Laravel & AngularJS)

- Timesheet Management Project manage the work details in day wise.
- Prepared DB Schema & involved in service architectural design
- This Project handle the different user goups such as Super User, Agency, Client, Manage, Contractor. Agency users created by Super User.
- Client, Manager and Contractor users created by Agency. TimeSheet Project Manage the Invoice Report and Purchase Orders.

#### Electronic Health Management (Laravel & JQuery)

- Electronic Health Management manage the health records online
- Prepared DB Schema & involved in service architectural design
- Electronic Health Record manage user groups Super user, Partner, Dealer, Doctor, Lab, Pharmacy, Service Center and member.
- Electronic health record using instamojo payment gateway
- Membership plans 1 Member 1 Month Package, 1 Member 1 Year Package, 4 Member 1 Year Family Package, 6 Member 1 Year Family Package

#### infySEC and DoWebScan WebSite (Joomla CMS)

infySEC WebSite developed the Company WebSite using Joomla CMS and MySQL. Created the joomla components and integrated the third party components.

#### **EDUCATION**

# **Master of Computer Application**

Erode Sengunthar Engineering College, Erode.

06/2010 - 06/2013 82 GPA

# **B.Sc (Computer Science)**

Karuppannan Mariappan College of Arts and Science, Muthur.

06/2007 - 06/2010 66 %

# **Higher Secondary School**

Govt. Hr. Sec School, Vaiyappamalai, Namakkal.

06/2006 - 06/2007

#### **SSLC**

Govt. Boys Sec School, Sivagiri, Erode

06/2004 - 06/2005